舰长日志：
Captain's log:
我们正环绕Psi2000的轨道飞行
Our position: Orbiting Psi 2000,
这颗古老的行星，现在已是冰冻荒地
an ancient world, now a frozen wasteland
正分崩离析地走向灭亡
about to rip apart in its death throes.
我们的任务是接回在下面的一队科研小组
Our mission: Pick up a scientific party below,
观测这颗行星毁灭的历程
observe the disintegration of the planet.
- 检查生命支持系统 - 是，长官
- Check out the life-support systems. - Right, sir.
所有生命支持系统都被关闭了，长官
All life systems were off, sir.
她是被勒死的
Someone strangled this woman.
- 后面还有四个 - 死了？
- The other four are back there. - Dead?
- 是的，长官 - 工程师在岗吗？
- Right, sir. - Engineer at his post?
他就像是毫不在意的冻僵在那
He's frozen there like he didn't care.
其他人呢？
The rest?
哦…
Well...
您最好自己去看一下，史波克先生
Better look for yourself, Mr. Spock.
有一个人当时在淋浴，还穿戴整齐
One man was taking a shower fully clothed.
我们一定要避免直接接触这里的一切
Be certain we expose ourselves to nothing.
史波克呼叫进取号，是否收到？
Spock here. Do you read, Enterprise?
- 我是寇克，收到 - 全站人员死亡
- Kirk. Affirmative. - All station personnel are dead.
- 什么原因？ - 还不清楚，舰长
- what caused it? - Unknown, captain.
像是我们从未遇到过的情况
It's like nothing we've dealt with before.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务
Its five-year mission:
是去探索未知的新世界
To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命与新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢的航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
-=THE LAST FANTASY=-
荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：土豆爱 曼珠 kmdangdangli
校对：心痕依，Micezhang，xjCGI
第一季第四集
率真时间
舰长日志，星历1704.2
Captain's log, stardate 1704.2.
待接回的科学小组人员全部死亡
The science party we were to have picked up has been found dead.
生命支持系统被关闭
Life-support systems had been turned off,
全站人员冰冻至死，情况极其罕见
station personnel frozen to death, conditions highly unusual.
同时，我们依然在环绕轨道上继续执行任务
Meanwhile, we remain in orbit to complete our mission:
对行星毁灭的近距离科学观测
Close scientific measurement of the break-up of this planet.
- 你收到我刚才的通知了吗，史考特先生？ - 收到了，长官
- Did you receive my signal, Mr. Scott? - Yes, sir.
开始净化处理
Decontaminate.
- 这里是舰长 - 史波克和托莫伦已经返回，长官
- Captain here. - Spock and Tormolen aboard, sir.
我们正在传送室对他们进行净化处理
We're holding them in the chamber for decontamination.
最好让医疗队也给他们检查一下
Better have Medicine look them over too.
告诉史波克先生，10分钟后我去那见他
Tell Mr. Spock I’ll meet him there in ten minutes.
完毕
Kirk out.
没问题，乔，起来到那边去吧
You're fine, joe. Up and out of there.
史波克先生
Mr. Spock.
你的的脉搏242
Your pulse is 242.
基本没有血压
Your blood pressure is practically nonexistent,
如果你把你血管里的绿色物质称为血液的话
assuming you call that green stuff in your veins blood.
这些读数对我来说太正常不过了，医生，谢谢
The readings are perfectly normal for me, doctor. Thank you.
鉴于我的生理结构和你们不一样，我非常高兴
And as for my anatomy being different from yours, I am delighted.
- 舰长 - 他们怎么样？
- Captain. - How are they?
- 他们很好，吉姆 - 相当糟糕，舰长
- They're fine, jim. - Terrible, captain.
很糟糕，他们坐在那里就好像什么都不在乎
It was terrible. They were just sitting like they didn't care.
不管发生了什么，他们都无所谓
Whatever was happening, they didn't care.
- 我一直在想… - 你一直在想
- I keep wondering... - You keep wondering
人们是否真的应该到那里去
if man was meant to be out here.
你一直在思考，你一直在不停工作
You keep wondering, and you keep signing on.
有何推测，史波克先生，那里发生什么事了？
Any guesses, Mr. Spock? Any idea what happened down there?
我只能说，舰长，那里状况很怪异
I wish I could say, captain. Circumstances were quite bizarre.
但是录影带可能会给我们一些提示
However, our record tapes may show us something.
6个死人，6个人死了
Six dead. Six people dead.
- 你最好休息一下 - 是，先生
- You better get some rest. - Yes, sir.
史波克先生，准备好录影带，看看能否找到答案
Set up those tapes, Mr. Spock. We'll see if the answers are there.
- 实验结果报告，医生 - 谢谢，克莉丝汀
- The lab status report, doctor. - Oh, thank you, Christine.
请放下一盘
Next tape, please.
- 光谱分析带，先生 - 谢谢
- Spectroanalysis tape, sir. - Thank you.
好像他们失去了理智，被下了药
Almost as though they were irrational, drugged.
有个工程师看起来对一切都毫不在意，一个女人被勒死了
An engineer there, apparently oblivious to everything, a woman strangled,
一个组员手里拿着相位手枪
a crewman with a phaser pistol in his hand.
他使用计算机房，就好像那里是一个娱乐场所
He'd used the computer room as if it were an amusement gallery.
还有一个着装整齐的人在淋浴时被冻死了
And a fully clothed man frozen to death in a shower.
场面如果不是那么可怕，这会是相当有趣的
If the image wasn't so ugly, it'd be laughable.
- 绅士们，还没有什么推测吗？ - 肯定不是药物中毒
- Not even a theory, gentlemen? - Definitely not drugs or intoxication.
对录影带的生化分析已经排除了这点
The bioanalysis on the tapes prove that conclusively.
可能是某种我们闻所未闻的空间癫狂症
Could be some form of space madness we've never heard of.
但一定是有某种病因的
But it would have to be caused by something.
我们的光谱仪显示并没有污染
Our spectro readings showed no contamination,
并不存在异常元素
no unusual elements present.
或者说在三录仪里没有记录
Or at least none your tricorders could register.
仪器是被设计来记录特定类型的东西
Instruments register only those things they're designed to register.
宇宙里仍存在无限的未知
Space still contains infinite unknowns.
地球科学部需要对这个星球的解体
Earth science needs the closest possible measurement
进行尽可能的近距离观测
of the break-up of this planet.
为此，进取号要在相当紧密的环绕轨道上运行
To do this, we need the Enterprise in a critically tight orbit. Question:
问题是，那些人遇到的事情
Could what happened down there to those people
是否会给这艘星舰及其船员带来不寻常的危险
create any unusual danger to this vessel and crew?
我们会需要全舰的高效运作，舰长 那会是个很难掌控的轨道
We will need top efficiency, captain. It'll be a tricky orbit.
当一个行星开始消亡，可能会带来剧烈的变化
When a planet begins to go, there may be drastic changes
如引力、质量、磁场等
in gravity, mass, magnetic field.
先生们，开会的目的就是要根据你们的能力和经验
The purpose of a briefing, gentlemen, is to get me answers
为我找到答案
based on your abilities and experience.
在危险轨道上运行时，我们容不得任何意外
In a critical orbit, there's no time for surprise.
除非你们开始在舰桥穿戴整齐地淋浴
Unless you people on the bridge start taking showers with your clothes on,
否则我的引擎能把我们带离任何险境
my engines can pull us out of anything.
在接到您的命令后半秒钟我们就能曲速脱离轨道
We'll be warping out of orbit within a half-second of getting your command.
舰桥呼叫舰长
Bridge to captain.
我是寇克
Kirk here.
扫描仪显示星球磁场突然偏移4度
Scanners report sudden four-degree shift in planet magnetic field.
质量也发生了改变，先生
A change in mass also, sir.
开始了，不寻常的快速转变
It's beginning. Unusually rapid shifts.
我们马上赶到，上尉
On our way, lieutenant.
我记住你的半秒钟了，史考特
I'll hold you to that half-second, Scotty.
花剑，它是一把很细长的决斗用的剑
Foil. It's a rapier, a thin sword.
好吧，那你用它干什么？
All right. So, what do you do with it?
什么意思，“用它干什么？”
What do you mean, "What do you do with it?"
自我防卫，蓄意伤害，烤羊肉串？
Self-defence, mayhem, shish kebab?
- 你试试吧 - 试什么？
- You practice. - For what?
嗨，乔伊
Hi, Joey.
上周他想让我对植物学产生兴趣
Last week it was botany he was trying to get me interested in.
我应该收集叶子、植物种籽等等
I was supposed to be collecting leaves, plant specimens...
你的态度不对
Your attitude is all wrong.
练习击剑能让你眼明手快，雄姿昂昂
Fencing tones the muscle, sharpens the eye, improves the posture.
你和他说说，乔伊，给他讲讲
You tell him, Joey. Explain to him.
嘿，乔伊
Hey, joey.
- 你没事吧？ - 离我远点
- You feeling all right? - Get off me.
你没我级别高，你也没有尖耳朵，所以别管我的闲事
You don't rank me, and you don't have pointed ears, so just get off my neck.
- 他怎么了？ - 没事
- What's with him? - Nothing.
注意：轮机室待命警戒
Attention: Engine room on standby alert.
全体在岗人员到舰桥集合，通话完毕
All duty personnel to the bridge. Acknowledge.
你确定没事吗，乔？我们要走了
You sure you're all right now, Joe? We've gotta leave.
我们都是伪君子
We're all a bunch of hypocrites.
用我们的鼻子嗅探和我们无关的事情
Stick our noses into something that we've got no business.
- 我们到底在这里干什么？ - 放松，乔
- What are we doing here anyway? - Take it easy, joe.
只会给我们自己带来痛苦和麻烦
Bring pain and trouble with us.
把男人女人都留在冰冻的星球上直到他们死掉
Leave men and women stuck out on freezing planets until they die.
我们在太空里做什么？好处吗？
What are we doing out here in space? Good?
有什么好处？
What good?
我们正在污染太空，毁掉太空
We're polluting it, destroying it.
我们没有权利到这里来，没有权利
We've got no business being out here, no business.
- 放松，好吗？ - 冷静一下
- Take it easy now, would you? - Now calm down.
如果一个人要飞，他就要有翅膀
If a man was supposed to fly, he'd have wings.
如果他要在太空里呆着，他就不需要呼吸空气
If he was supposed to be out in space, he wouldn't need air to breathe.
就不需要生命支持系统来阻止被冻死
Wouldn't need life-support systems to keep him from freezing to death.
- 乔伊，把刀放下，好吗？ - 你完全失去理智了，乔
- Hey, joey, put the knife down, huh? - You're all steamed up, joe.
我们不属于这里
We don't belong here.
这里不是我们的地方，不是
It's not ours, not ours.
毁灭、观察…
Destroying and watching...
我们不属于这儿
We don't belong.
我不属于这儿
I don't belong.
那里有6个人死了
Six people died down there.
为什么我应该活下去呢？
Why do I deserve to live?
- 你要干什么，乔？ - 嘿，乔伊，把刀放下
- What are you doing, joe? - Hey, joey, put the knife down.
- 别做傻事 - 放开，放开！
- Don't be a fool. - Let go, let go!
- 让我拿着刀子 - 快放手！
- Let me have the knife! - Please let go!
乔伊，别做傻事
joey, don't be a fool.
乔伊…
joey...
乔伊，把刀给我
joey, give me the knife.
紧急情况！娱乐室，39区！我们需要医疗队！
Emergency! Rec room, area 39! We need medics!
舰长日志，补充：
Captain's log, supplemental:
我们的轨道，正在收紧，我们对效率的需求，是关键性的
Our orbit, tightening. Our need for efficiency, critical.
但对我们来说未知的
But unknown to us,
则是已经被带到舰上的罕见疾病
a totally new and unusual disease has been brought aboard.
- 相对引力在增加，先生 - 自动补偿，莱利先生
- Relative gravity increasing, sir. - Compensate, Mr. Riley.
- 是，长官 - 磁场继续变化，长官
- Yes, sir. - Magnetic field continuing to shift, sir.
星球质量继续缩水
Planet continuing to shrink in mass.
- 史波克先生？ - 所有扫描站正在监控
- Mr. Spock? - All scanning stations manned,
所有记录器功能正常，舰长
all recorders functioning, captain.
现在轨道稳定了，长官
Orbit steady now, sir.
显然，这个星球萎缩的比预期要快很多
Obviously, this planet is condensing more rapidly than expected.
很有研究价值
A valuable study.
我们或许能看到地球遥远的未来
We may be seeing Earth's distant future.
在太阳熄灭前，这个星球很明显和你们的地球类似
Before its sun went dark, this planet was remarkably similar to yours.
- 舰舵响应非常好，舰长 - 很好
- Helm answering nicely, captain. - Good.
通讯状态报告，舰长
Communications status, captain.
- 托莫伦的记录？ - 精神病史档案，性格分析
- Tormolen's record? - Psychiatric file, personality quotients.
- 他想要自杀？ - 是否是自愿值得怀疑
- Was he trying to kill himself? - It's doubtful he meant to.
他很混乱，一直在折磨自己
He was confused, self-tortured.
听起来不像是我认识的那个人
Doesn't sound like the man I know.
他一直都很不自信
His capacity for self-doubt has always been rather high.
让我奇怪的是，什么让他如此强烈地表现出来
What puzzles me is what brought it to the surface with so much force.
他的呼吸频率在下降，医生
His breathing rate is dropping, doctor.
用呼吸器补偿
Compensate with the respirator.
准备缝合
Stand by to close.
正在缝合
Closing.
- 怎么了？ - 相对引力增加了，先生
- What is it? - Relative gravity increase, sir.
好像是那个星球抓着我们猛拉一样
Like the planet reached out and yanked at us.
进行补偿
Compensate.
轨道稳定了，先生
Orbit steady now, sir.
我可能有点紧张
Maybe a little nervous, I guess.
这不可能啊
This shouldn't be happening.
这人应该好起来才对
This man should be getting stronger.
你确定呼吸器功能完好？
You sure the respirator is functioning properly?
是的，医生
Yes, doctor.
为什么他就快死了呢？
Well, why is this man dying?
皮下注射
Hypo.
他死了，医生
He's dead, doctor.
伤口并没那么严重啊
The wounds were not that severe.
这里是麦考伊，寇克舰长请到医务室
This is McCoy. Captain Kirk to Sickbay.
乌乎拉，监视通讯状态
Uhura, monitor communications.
- 告诉麦考伊我有空就过去 - 是，长官
- Tell McCoy I'll be there when I can. - Yes, sir.
星球的解体马上开始，舰长，萎缩速度在加快
Planet break-up is imminent, captain. Shrinking in size at an increasing rate.
随着星球继续萎缩
As the planet continues to shrink in size,
它的表面离我们越来越远
its surface moves away from us.
我们要盘旋逼近从而保持同样的距离
Forcing us to spiral down to maintain the same distance from it.
没错，我们必须时刻准备好
Exactly. We must be prepared to respond instantly
应付任何突发变化
to any sudden change.
- 舰桥呼叫轮机室 - 这里是史考特，舰长
- Engine room from bridge. - Scott here, captain.
坚守船舵，史考特，如果我们需要动力，就要尽快得到
Tie into the helm, Scotty. If we should call for power, we'll want it fast.
没问题，先生，你会得到的
No problem, sir. You'll have it.
收缩率看起来稳定了
Rate of compaction seems constant.
那我就去看看好医生找我干什么了
Then I'll go see what the good doctor wants.
有任何变化通知我，史波克先生
Keep me informed of any change, Mr. Spock.
收到
Acknowledged.
真不知道是这星球的问题还是乔的问题…
Don't know if it's this planet or what happened with Joe...
- 我像个新郎官似的出汗不止 - 是啊，我也一样
- I'm sweating like a bridegroom. - Yeah. Me too.
嘿，凯文，何不跟我去健身房呢，我的朋友？
Hey, why don't you come down to the gym with me, Kevin, my lad?
- 现在？ - 有何不可？
- Now? - Why not?
- 适度锻炼一会儿可以缓解一下紧张 - 嘿，苏鲁，那——？
- A light workout will take the edge off. - Hey, Sulu, what about--?
嘿，苏鲁，别犯傻了
Hey, Sulu, don't be a fool.
回来
Come.
肠壁的损伤重不至死
Intestinal damage wasn't that severe.
我抢救了那么长时间，他应该能活下来才对
I got to him in plenty of time. That man should still be alive.
他的死只有一个原因，吉姆，那就是他不想活了，他放弃了
Only reason he died, jim, is he didn't wanna live. He gave up.
- 那只是推测，不是事实 - 嗯，有可能的，这是可能的
- That's a supposition, not a fact. - Well, that may be. It may be.
我以前也有过对病人束手无策的时候，可不像这次似的
I've lost patients before, but not like that.
乔不是那样的人，他是不可能放弃的
Not joe's kind. That kind of man doesn't give up.
巧合吗？
Coincidence?
可能吧
Maybe.
你的意思是他去过那星球的表面
You mean that joe was down on the planet's surface,
你想问我这是不是有关联？
and you're gonna ask me if it's connected?
我就是想这么问
That's exactly what I was gonna ask.
吉姆，他已经净化处理过了，也进行了医学检查
jim, he was decontaminated, he's been medically checked,
所有我们知道的检查方式都已经做过了
we've run every test we know for everything we know.
- 那还不够好 - 我们把所有可能的都检查了
- That's not good enough. - We're doing everything possible.
老骨头，我想要那些不可能也被检查出来
Bones, I want the impossible checked out too.
苏鲁先生怎么没在岗位上？
Why isn't Mr. Sulu at this station?
磁性拉力已经补偿，轨道稳定中
Magnetic pull compensated for. Orbit steady.
- 你来接手，兰德 - 是，长官
- Take over here, Rand. - Yes, sir.
你还没回答我的问题，苏鲁在哪儿？
You haven't answered my question. Where is Mr. Sulu?
莱利在旁，无须惊慌
Have no fear, O'Riley's here.
- 一个爱尔兰人可值一万个—— - 你已被解除职务，莱利先生
- And one Irishman is worth 10,000-- - You're relieved, Mr. Riley.
乌乎拉上尉，你接手这个岗位
Lieutenant Uhura, take over this station.
- 好的，长官 - 我就喜欢这样
- Yes, sir. - Now that's what I like.
女人也上阵，普选权就这么说的
Let the women work too. Universal suffrage.
- 莱利先生，请到医务室报告 - 医务室？
- Report to Sickbay, Mr. Riley. - Sickbay?
我正要去呢，长官
Exactly where I was heading, sir.
安全人员，莱利先生正向医务室去，请看着他到达
Security, Mr. Riley is headed for Sickbay. See to it he arrives.
寇克船长请到舰桥来
Captain Kirk to the bridge.
乔呢？
Where's Joe?
- 呃—— - 他死了，是不是？
- Well-- - He died, didn't he?
是的
Yes.
你知道吗…
You know something...
…你的双眼如此动人
...you have such lovely eyes.
漂亮的女士
Pretty lady.
我知道他是你的朋友，对你肯定是个很大的打击
I know he was a friend of yours. This must be a terrible shock.
你知道乔错在哪儿了吗？
You know what Joe's mistake was?
他的出身不是爱尔兰人
He wasn't born an Irishman.
黎塞留，小心了！
Richelieu, beware!
站住
Stand.
别动
No farther.
你休想逃走
No escape for you.
想离开这片林子，要么血肉相抵
You either leave this bois bloodied
要么让你的剑来饮我的血
or with my blood on your swords.
胆小鬼！
Cowards!
- 布伦特上尉，接替乌乎拉小姐 - 是，长官
- Lieutenant Brent, relieve Miss Uhura. - Yes, sir.
他们有什么症状？
What were their symptoms?
目前的阶段还没有出现暴力倾向，但有轻微的迷失
Non-violent at this stage. Slightly disoriented.
莱利看起来对自己相当满意，他好像——
Riley seemed rather pleased with himself, as if he were--
失去理性了
Irrational.
或者嗑药了
Or drugged.
- 没错 - 接安全人员，乌乎拉上尉
- Precisely. - Security, Lieutenant Uhura.
- 好的，长官 - 苏鲁和莱利，一旦找到立即禁闭
- Yes, sir. - Sulu and Riley, locate and confine.
我要每个接触过他们的船员都进行医学检查
I want every crewman who comes in contact with them medically checked.
长官，二号甲板，第三走廊报告说有骚乱发生
Sir, level two, corridor three reports a disturbance.
苏鲁拿着剑…
Mr. Sulu chasing crewmen...
…在追赶船员
...with a sword.
- 交给安全人员处理 - 有意思，规律出现了
- Put security on it. - Fascinating. A pattern is developing.
先是托莫伦
First Tormolen,
潜藏的个性被逼着表现了出来
hidden personality traits being forced to the surface.
然后是莱利，幻想自己是爱尔兰国王的后裔
Then Riley, who fancies himself a descendant of Irish kings.
现在是苏鲁，认为自己是十八世纪的侠盗
And now Sulu, who is at heart a swashbuckler out of your 18th century.
- Psi2000星球现状如何？ - 引力正在增加
- Present condition of Psi 2000? - Gravity pull increasing.
我们已移动了2%，按理应该稳定了
We've shifted two percent and should stabilize.
- 舵手，稳定位置 - 船舵不听使唤啊
- Helmsman, stabilize position. - Helm is not answering to control.
- 曲速离开这里 - 引擎没有反应，长官
- Warp us out of here. - No response from engines, sir.
那就用脉冲动力，把我们推离这个轨道
Impulse power then. Blast us out of this orbit.
脉冲引擎也罢工了，长官
Impulse engines also dead, sir.
轮机室，我们需要动力！
Engine room, we need power!
史考特，回答！
Mr. Scott, acknowledge!
我们失去了控制
Our controls are dead.
接管这里
Take her.
黎塞留，你终于出现了
Richelieu, at last.
苏鲁，把这个——
Sulu, put that--
- 把这东西放下！ - 为了荣誉，为了女王和法国
- Put that thing away! - For honour, queen and France.
苏鲁！
Sulu!
苏鲁，把剑给我
Sulu, give me that.
- 苏鲁！ - 我会保护你的，美丽的小姐
- Sulu! - I'll protect you, fair maiden.
抱歉，我不美也不要保护
Sorry, neither.
邪恶的黎塞留！
Foul Richelieu!
我有时候很想你教教我这一手
I'd like you to teach me that sometime.
史考特，我们需要动力
Scotty, we need power.
轮机室，回答！
Engine room, acknowledge!
- 你在召唤我吗，长官？ - 你是谁？
- You rang, sir? - Who's this?
我是进取号星舰的舰长，凯文·托马斯·莱利
This is Captain Kevin Thomas Riley of the starship Enterprise.
- 你是谁？ - 我是寇克舰长
- And who is this? - This is Captain Kirk.
给我滚出轮机室，史考特轮机长在哪儿？
Get out of the engine room. Where's Mr. Scott?
我已经解除了他的职务
I’ve relieved Mr. Scott of his duties.
厨师们，现在注意了，你们的舰长在发话呢
And now, attention, cooks. This is your captain speaking.
我要给所有船员双份冰激凌
I would like double portions of ice cream for the entire crew.
- 明白怎么做吧，嗯？ - 是的，长官
- Clear that too, will you? - Yes, sir.
现在呢
And now,
你们的舰长将演唱一首古代爱尔兰人的最爱
your captain will render an ancient Irish favourite.
“我会再次带你回家”
I'll take you home again
舰长，以我们现在的下降速度
Captain. At our present rate of descent,
20分钟后将进入星球的大气层
we have less than 20 minutes before we enter planet atmosphere.
然后烧成灰烬，我知道的，史波克！
And burn up. I know, Mr. Spock!
舰长日志，星历1704.4：
Captain's log, stardate 1704.4:
星舰失去控制，正在向Psi2000星球盘旋下降
Ship out of control, spiralling down towards planet Psi 2000.
在没有引擎动力和船舵控制的情况下 我们还有十九分钟活命
we have 19 minutes of life left without engine power or helm control.
- 莱利怎么进去的？ - 他说你让我们到舰桥去
- How did Riley get in there? - He said you wanted us on the bridge.
他切断了船舵的控制和动力
He's cut off helm and power.
他还关上了门，锁定了门的机械装置
He shut the door and locked off the mechanism.
- 你不能接通辅助装置吗？ - 他通过主控面板
- Can't you get to the auxiliary? - He's hooked everything
把一切都锁定了
through the main panel.
去我办公室把舱壁的设计图拿来
Get up to my office and pull the plans for this bulkhead.
开门的唯一方法
The only way to get that door open
就是切断这些墙内的电路
is to cut through these wall circuits here.
“我看过他们的褪色和枯萎”
I've watched them fade away and die
- 状况报告，各区的 - 船尾军官室发生打斗
- Status reports, all sections. - A fight in the aft wardroom.
安全人员报告船员间的冲突在增加
Security reports incidents among the crewmen are increasing.
警戒级别提升至B2，封锁主要区域
Go to alert Baker Two. Seal off main sections.
所有甲板，警戒级别提升至B2
All decks, alert system B2.
重复一遍，警戒级别提升至B2
Repeat, go to alert condition Baker Two.
封锁所有主要区域，待命
Seal off all main sections. Stand by.
已封锁，不管那是什么病，但愿波及范围最小化
Sealed off, if we can minimize the spread of whatever this is.
- 继续警戒状态，上尉 - 我操作不了，长官
- Continue the alert, lieutenant. - I can't, sir.
他切断了警戒线路
He's cut off the alert channels.
乌乎拉上尉，你打断了我的歌唱
Lieutenant Uhura, you've interrupted my song.
很遗憾，但是今晚不能给你冰激凌了
I'm sorry, but there'll be no ice cream for you tonight.
- 切断他 - 我没办法，长官，没有可行的办法
- Cut him off. - I can't, sir. There's no way to do it.
注意了，船员们，我是莱利舰长
Attention, crew. This is Captain Riley.
今晚1900时在保龄球馆将会有一场正式舞会
There will be a formal dance in the bowling alley at 19:00 hours tonight.
- 待命吧 - 没办法，舰长
- Stand by. - No way, captain.
他控制了主控面板
He controls the main power panels.
他在下面可以直接控制所有线路
He can override any channel from down there.
还剩十七分钟，长官
Seventeen minutes left, sir.
医务室呼叫舰桥
Sickbay to bridge.
- 你可以连接我到医务室吗？ - 我能听到你，吉姆
- Can you tie me into the Sickbay? - I'm getting you, Jim.
听着，你能让这鬼星舰保持平衡吗？
Look, can you keep this beast level?
我已使苏鲁镇定下来，我们即将为他做检测
I've got Sulu tranquilized, and we're running tests on him.
目前为止，在他的血液里无任何异常
So far, there's nothing unusual in his bloodstream.
身体机能看似正常
Body functions seem normal.
莱利才是眼下棘手的问题，医生
Riley's the immediate problem, doctor.
你有没有什么办法，让他恢复理智？
Is there any way, anything you can do to snap him out of it?
答案是否定的，除非我的这些检测能有进展
Negative, until I can get a little further on these tests.
我是莱利舰长，船员们，我有一些补充命令
This is Captain Riley. Crew, I have some additional orders.
未来，所有的女船员
In the future, all female crew members will wear their hair
要披肩散发
loosely about their shoulders.
但要限制你们化妆，女人们
And use restraint in putting on your makeup, women.
女人看上去不该浓妆艳抹的
Women should not look made up.
现在呢，船员们，作为补偿我要再唱一遍…
And now, crew, I will render "Kathleen"...
…“凯瑟琳”！
...one more time!
求你了，别再唱了
Please, not again.
“我会再次带你回家，凯瑟琳”
I'll take you home again, Kathleen
“我看过他们的褪色和枯萎”
I've watched them fade away and die
我已经在上面安好了跨接器，我给你信号前原地待命
I've set the jumpers up there. Stand by till I give you a signal.
“泪水模糊了你动人的眼睛”
And tears bedim your loving eyes
“哦，我会带你回家，凯瑟琳”
Oh, I’ll take you home, Kathleen
轮机室呼叫舰桥，请试一下船舵
Engineering to bridge. Try your helm.
你们应该有足够的动力保证星舰稳定了
You'll have enough power to keep her stabilized.
来，让我们研究一下
Here, let's have a look at that.
还剩十六分钟，舰长，我们稳定下来了，但仍在盘旋下降
Sixteen minutes left, captain. We've stabilized, but spiralling down.
紧急信号，舰长
Emergency signal, captain.
四号和五号甲板都打作一团了，陷入混乱中
Both decks four and five, fights and disorders.
- 给我接医务室 - 我不能接通医务室的通话系统
- Get me Sickbay. - I have no intercom for Sickbay.
- 他在不断转换着线路 - 看看你能不能帮上麦考伊医生什么忙
- He keeps switching channels on me. - See if you can help Dr. McCoy.
最好先去看看史考特，让他快一点
Better check Scotty first, move him faster.
他必须穿透舱壁
He's gotta get through that bulkhead.
船员，去实验室报道
Crewman, report to the lab.
怎么回事？
What's going on?
我想到舰桥去，这位船员不让我过去
I'm trying to get to the bridge, and this crewman won't let me by.
- 船员，站到一边 - 哦，好，是的，长官
- Crewman, stand aside. - Oh, well, yes, sir.
- “我会再次带你回家，贾宁” - 史波克！
- I’ll take you home again, janeen - Spock!
- 舰长口信 - 告诉他我正在尽力
- Message from the captain. - Tell him I'm doing my best.
- 如果我切断了错误的电路—— - 我们还剩十四分钟了
- If I cut through the wrong circuits-- - We have 14 minutes left.
就算我们遭受全方位敌袭，也再快不了了
Even if we were under full-scale attack, I couldn't move any faster,
不能保持一个安全系数
not and maintain a safety factor.
以你现在进行的速度，计算显示
At the rate you're proceeding, calculations show
你将会比剩余时间多用一分半钟完成
that you'll take a minute and a half more than we have left.
你担负不起这个安全系数
You can't afford a safety factor.
活体组织检查实验室
Biopsy Lab.
活检室，我的报告呢？
Biopsy, where's my report?
活检室，回答我
Biopsy, come in.
哈里森，我的报告呢？
Harrison, where's my report?
- 我要去趟实验室 - 长官？
- I'm going to the lab. - Sir?
- 什么事？ - 镇定剂正在失效
- Yes? - The tranquilizer's wearing off.
哦，好，我现在需要他清醒
Oh, good. I'll need him conscious now.
继续使用K1和k3程序检查他
Continue to examine him on circuits K1 and 3.
当然可以了，医生
Of course, doctor.
把他弄出去
Get him out of here.
我本可以早点过来的，但是船员穆迪——
I would've gotten here sooner, but Crewman Moody--
- 你来掌舵 - 长官？
- Take the helm. - Sir?
- 掌舵！ - 遵命，长官
- Take the helm! - Yes, sir.
- 现在呢再来一遍！ - 至少尝试切断他的声音好吧！
- And now one more time! - At least try cutting him off!
长官，如果我能做到，你觉得我会——？
Sir, if I could cut him off, don't you think I'd--?
- “我会再次带你回家，凯瑟琳” - 好吧，长官，我会再试的
- I’ll take you home again, Kathleen - Yes, sir. I'll keep trying.
对不起
Sorry.
“穿过那自然广阔的海洋”
Across the ocean wild and wide
- 史考特？ - 轮机室
- Scotty? - Engine room.
我们只剩下十二分钟了
We've got 12 minutes left.
重启引擎至少还得两到三分钟
It'll take at least two or three of them to get the engines up to power.
顺利的话，还来得及，长官
Then we'll make it, sir, if all goes right.
墙一钻通就叫我过来，完毕
Call me when you've cut through. I'll wanna be there. Kirk out.
护士？
Nurse?
麦考伊医生在哪里？
Where is Dr. McCoy?
去实验室了
He's gone to the lab.
实验室？
Lab?
实验室，请回答，我是史波克
Lab, respond please. Spock here.
实验室？
Lab?
- 史波克先生 - 有事吗，护士？
- Mr. Spock. - What is it, nurse?
史波克先生…
Mr. Spock...
瓦肯星上的男人对自己的女人都很奇怪
...the men from Vulcan treat their women strangely.
至少，大家都这么说
At least, people say that.
但你有一半人类血统
But you're part human too.
我知道你不想…
I know you don't...
也不会…
You couldn't...
伤害我
...hurt me.
对吗？
Would you?
我爱上了你，史波克先生
I'm in love with you, Mr. Spock.
你…
You...
不论你是人类史波克…
...the human Mr. Spock...
还是瓦肯人史波克
...the Vulcan Mr. Spock.
- 护士，你不该… - 叫我克莉丝汀
- Nurse, you shouldn't-- - Christine. Please.
我了解你的处境，你是如此诚实
I see things, how honest you are.
我懂你的感受
I know how you feel.
你外表冷酷，可内心却充满情感
You hide it, but you do have feeling.
那些对你的冷嘲热讽一定让你很难受
Oh, how we must hurt you, torture you.
我能控制我的情感
I'm in control of my emotions.
别人信，可我却不信
The others believe that. I don't.
我爱你
I love you.
不知为何，但我就是爱你，我真的爱你
I don't know why, but I love you. I do love you.
就爱这样的你
just as you are.
噢…我爱你
Oh, I love you.
对不起
I'm sorry.
舰长已前往轮机室，史波克先生
Captain is en route Engineering, Mr. Spock.
你能接管舰桥吗？请回答
Can you take the bridge? Acknowledge.
对不起
I am sorry.
- 叫我克莉丝汀 - 克莉丝汀
Christine.
舰桥呼叫医务室，史波克先生在吗？
Bridge to Sickbay. Is Mr. Spock there?
史波克先生，请回答
Mr. Spock, would you please acknowledge?
“我会带你回家，凯瑟琳”
I will take you home, Kathleen
马上就好，长官
Almost ready, sir.
“那里没有痛苦”
To where your heart will feel no pain
“待田野碧绿如玉”
When the fields are fresh and green
“我就带你回家”
I'll take you to your home
- 准备就绪，长官 - 跟我冲进去
- Ready, sir. - Follow me through.
相位枪调至击晕档
Put your phasers on stun.
别轻易开火除非他有武器，行动
Don't fire unless he's armed. Go.
“我会带…”
I'll take--
今晚没有舞会了
No dance tonight.
把他带走
Get him out of here.
（简报室）
我能控制我的情感
I'm in control of my emotions.
控制我的…
Control of my...
我是名军官
I am an officer.
军官
Officer.
我的职责…
My duty...
我的职责是…
My duty is to...
太迟了
Too late.
对不起
I am sorry.
二【史波克用数偶数克制情感】
Two.
四
Four.
六
Six.
六乘…
Six times...
六加三十…
Six and 30...
- 史考特，时间不多了 - 舰桥呼叫舰长
- Scotty, we haven't got much time left. - Bridge to captain.
- 我是寇克 - 已经进入行星大气层
- Kirk here. - Entering planet's outer atmosphere.
- 舰长 - 怎么了？
- Captain. - What is it?
他把所有引擎都给关了
He's turned the engines off.
完全冷却了，重新启动需要半小时
Completely cold. It'll take 30 minutes to regenerate them.
星舰外壳开始变热，舰长
Ship's outer skin is beginning to heat, captain.
轨道测绘仪显示还剩八分钟
Orbit plot shows we have about eight minutes left.
- 史考特 - 我没法改变物理法则
- Scotty. - I can't change the laws of physics.
必须给我半小时
I've got to have 30 minutes.
舰长日志，补充：
Captain's log, supplemental:
进取号已失控，正在盘旋下坠
The Enterprise, spiralling down, out of control.
与大气产生摩擦
Ship's outer skin heating rapidly
致使外壳温度剧增
due to friction with planet atmosphere.
- 给我二十多分钟… - 史考特，只有六分钟
- Maybe 22, 23 minutes-- - Scotty, we've got six.
物质和反物质低温下不能混合
Captain, you can't mix matter and antimatter cold.
否则将会引发一次最大的爆炸，这将会是自…
We'd go up in the biggest explosion since--
均衡引擎动力便可使二者聚爆【聚爆可使引擎在低温下启动】
We can balance our engines into a controlled implosion.
理论上可以，但从来没试过
That's only a theory. It's never been done.
舰桥，找到史波克了吗？
Bridge, have you found Mr. Spock yet?
只有万分之一的成功率
If you wanted to chance odds of 10,000-1 maybe,
还要一个计算机组运算数周，才能得出公式
assuming we had a row of computers working weeks on the right formula.
史波克先生不在舰桥，舰长
Mr. Spock is not on the bridge, captain.
刚才我还在舰桥
I was on the bridge.
嘿…大夫，我怎么会在这儿？
Hey, doc, what am I doing here?
麦考伊呼叫活检室，已经找到病因，开始准备血清
McCoy to Bio. We've isolated it. Start preparing serum.
- 是啥呀，医生？ - 是水
- What, doctor? - It's water.
行星上的水不知为何转变成了结构复杂的分子链
On this planet, water's changed to a complex chain of molecules.
- 那是啥，医生？ - 是被忽略的一点
- What's that, doctor? - That's how we missed it.
它通过汗液传染
It passed through perspiration.
一旦渗入血管，就会像酒精一样
Once in the bloodstream, it acts like alcohol.
降低判断力及自制力
Depresses the centres of judgment, self-control.
派人去活检室！让大伙用血清治疗
Now get someone to the lab! Tell them the serum works
准备更多血清！
and start preparing more!
大夫，让我走吧，我好了
Doc, will you let me out of here? I'm all right.
让他走
Release him.
轮机人员，各就各位，轮机室，报告
Engineers, man your stations. Engine rooms, report.
循环室，报告
Cycling station, report.
准备以应急方式重启引擎
This will be an emergency restart of engines.
- 你跑哪去了？我到处… - 我母亲…
- Where have you been? I’ve been-- - My mother...
我从没对她说我爱她
I could never tell her I loved her.
就剩四分钟了，也许五分钟
We've got four minutes, maybe five.
一位来自地球的女人却在一个鄙视爱和情感的
An Earth woman, living on a planet where love,
- 星球上生活 - 我们必须冒一次满负荷启动的风险
- emotion is bad taste. - We've got to risk a full-power start.
引擎被关闭了，没时间启动了，听见了吗？
The engines were shut off. No time to regenerate them. Do you hear me?
- 只有冒险用满负荷启动 - 我尊敬我的父亲和那的风俗
- We've got to risk a full-power start. - I respected my father, our customs.
人类的血统让我感到羞耻
I was ashamed of my Earth blood.
吉姆…
jim...
你我的友谊有时令我羞愧
When I feel friendship for you, I'm ashamed.
张大耳朵，听我说！
You've got to hear me!
我们需要一个方程式！用聚爆这个险招
We need a formula! We've got to risk implosion!
没人试过
It's never been done.
知道吗，吉姆？
Understand, jim...
我一辈子都在隐藏自己的情感
...I've spent a whole lifetime learning to hide my feelings.
只有聚爆才是唯一出路
We've got to risk implosion. It's our only chance.
没人试过
It's never been done.
不用你重复，科学官！只要有理论，便可能会实现
Don't tell me that again, science officer! It's a theory. It's possible.
我们可能会变成一个最大的火球，规模不亚于太阳的爆炸
We may go up into the biggest ball of fire since the last sun exploded,
即便如此，都要抓住万分之一的机会
but we've gotta take that 1 in 10,000 chance.
舰桥呼叫舰长，轮机长想知道你是否找到…
Bridge to captain. Engineer asked did you find--
别再问史波克在哪了！我们正在说话！
Yes, I found Mr. Spock! I'm talking to Mr. Spock!
- 明白了吗？ - 是，长官
- Do you understand? - Yes, sir.
- 还剩三分半钟，舰长 - 我被感染了
- Three and a half minutes left, captain. - I've got it.
那种疾病
The disease.
爱
Love.
没有爱，你我都会好受些
You're better off without it, and I'm better off without mine.
这艘星舰…
This vessel...
我倾之以心血
I give.
她不断索取
She takes.
她剥夺了我的生活，我和她已成为一体
She won't permit me my life. I've got to live hers.
吉姆…
jim...
我有位美丽的文书
I have a beautiful yeoman.
你知道她有多美吗，史波克？
Have you noticed her, Mr. Spock?
你可以和她对视
You're allowed to notice her.
舰长却不行…
The captain's not permitted...
吉姆…
jim...
有一个混合的方程式
There is an intermix formula.
我终于明白为何…
Now I know why...
它被称为“她”【船只第三人称英文用she】
...it's called "she."
公式从未经过验证
It's never been tested.
理论上提出了反物质与时间的关系
It's a theoretical relationship between time and antimatter.
她有血有肉，我本可张开双臂
A flesh woman to touch,
拥抱她
to hold.
我们可以在海滩漫步
A beach to walk on.
哪怕就几天，让我放下肩负的重任
A few days, no braid on my shoulder.
舰长
Captain.
史考特
Scotty.
帮帮我
Help.
准备混合
Stand by to intermix.
我会从舰桥调用这个方程式
I'll call the formula in from the bridge.
已进入平流层，舰长
Entering upper stratosphere, captain.
船壳温度高达2170度
Skin temperature now 2170 degrees.
我必须挺住
I've got to hang on.
告诉他们，把走廊和涡轮电梯都清空
Tell them, clear the corridors, the turbo lift.
快
Hurry.
绝不放弃你
Never lose you.
绝不
Never.
舰桥
Bridge.
【罪人，悔改吧】
轮机室
Engine room.
准备好
We're set.
航线设为双曲式
Hyperbolic course.
方向，长官？
Direction, sir?
方向…
Direction...
无所谓，怎么来，就怎么走
It doesn't matter. The way we came.
航线已设定，长官
Course laid in, sir.
燃料温度？
Fuel temperature?
接近零度
Level.
没沙滩可走
No beach to walk on.
长官？
Sir?
加热反物质，温度840度
Raise antimatter 840 degrees.
需要四分钟
That'll take four minutes.
没时间了，只有冒险
We haven't the time. We'll have to risk it.
舰桥，已准备就绪
Bridge, we're ready.
启动
Engage.
- 你没事吧，吉姆？ - 你呢？
- Are you all right, Jim? - You?
解药找到了，一切已恢复正常
We've found a cure. We're over that part of it.
也就是说，我们成功了
Obviously, we were successful.
- 引擎聚爆成功 - 舰长
- The engines imploded. - Captain.
速度计无显示
My velocity gauge is off the scale.
引擎能量也没有显示
Engine power went off the scale as well.
目前的速度已超出正常空间的飞行速度
We're now travelling faster than is possible for normal space.
检查飞行时间，苏鲁
Check elapsed time, Mr. Sulu.
计时器正…
My chronometer is running...
往后跑，长官
...backwards, sir.
【星历…舰上时间…】
时间曲跃
Time warp.
我们回到了过去
We're going backward in time.
舵手，开始反转动力
Helm, begin reversing power.
慢些
Slowly.
船舵正常，长官
Helm answering, sir.
动力正在反转
Power reversing.
时间恢复正常，舰长
We're back to normal time, captain.
前进
Engines ahead.
一级曲速
Warp one.
一级曲速，长官
Warp one, sir.
- 史波克先生 - 是，长官
- Mr. Spock? - Yes, sir.
时间曲跃…
The time warp...
- 对我们有何影响？ - 我们回到了七十一小时前
- ...what did it do to us? - We've regressed in time 71 hours.
也就是三天前，舰长
It is now three days ago, captain.
过去的三天还能重新再过一遍
We have three days to live over again.
别再是过去的那三天
Not those last three days.
这的确呈现出一个有趣的启示，舰长
This does open some intriguing prospects, captain.
既然方程式有效
Since the formula worked,
我们便可以回到过去任意行星，任意年代
we can go back in time to any planet, any era.
总有一天会用得着，史波克先生
We may risk it someday, Mr. Spock.
恢复航线，前往下个目的地，苏鲁
Resume course to our next destination, Mr. Sulu.
航线已设定，长官
Course laid in, sir.
“她”继续稳健前行
Steady as she goes.
本集结束
-=The Last Fantasy=-
谢谢观赏